HARNAM SINGH ARORA

+91 8149737884 · <u>arora.harnam15@gmail.com</u> · My Portfolio · <u>LinkedIn Profile</u> Plot - 388, Sector 27A, Pradhikaran, Pune - 411044

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & TESTER

Software Tester and Developer with 2 years of experience in automation testing and programming. Proficient in **Java, Python, Selenium WebDriver** and **API testing** using **Karate.** Experienced in building automation frameworks, analyzing logs and providing value to both the QA team and Development Team.

STRENGTHS AND EXPERTISE

- Java, Python, SQL
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Selenium WebDriver
- Cucumber, Karate
- REST API Testing
- Time Management
- Communication
- Problem Solving

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cognizant

June 2022 - November 2023

Software Developer & Tester

- Established a complete test automation framework using Java, Selenium WebDriver, and Cucumber to test all core functionality of an e-Commerce application.
- Automated daily user functionalities like log in, product search, adding products to cart and checkout, greatly reducing the amount of manual testing and speeding up releases.
- Developed backend API testing using Karate to check responses, status codes and make sure everything worked together across services.
- Built a **Python** tool that processes log files and highlights errors or exceptions making it faster and easier for the team to find and fix issues.
- Collaborated with developers and testers at daily Agile meetings to become familiar with features; give early feedback around bugs, and make sure everything was ready before deadlines.

Forvia (Faurecia)

January 2022 - May 2022

R&D Tester

- Manually tested web application to make sure everything was working correctly too met the requirements.
- Ran repeated tests after updates (regression testing) to make sure the old features still worked and were not affected by any new bugs.
- Wrote detailed, clear test cases separating the steps to test the new functionalities and helped my team find bugs early on.
- Created simple and clean-looking landing email template with HTML and CSS that were used for campaigns and customer communications.

Prepca Pvt. Ltd.

February 2019 - November 2021

Team Leader / Operations Manager

- Started off as a computer operator and within 6 months I was elevated to Team Leader position for consistency in results and proactive approach.
- Supervised a small group and I was responsible for job assignment, quality checking, and data compliance and overall task delivery on time, every time.
- I helped make improvements to task processes by implementing minor improvements and enhancements to allow daily tasks to run faster and smoother.
- I trained new members of the team and educated users on how to navigate the platform appropriately in preparation for their examinations to ensure that they were comfortable and confident in the system.

EDUCATION

Savitribai Phule Pune University

Bachelor of Computer Application (BCA)

2018 - 2021

PROJECTS

Log File Analyzer (Python)

- Script that reads `.log` files and filters lines with 'ERROR' or 'Exception'.
- · Helped team quickly identify critical issues during testing.

E-Commerce Automation Testing

- · Automated UI flows using Java, Selenium WebDriver, and Cucumber.
- Used Karate to test REST APIs and ensure integration accuracy.

Personal Portfolio Website

- Built a responsive website with animated typing effect and project showcase.
- Tech used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript. Hosted via GitHub Pages.

Flappy Bird & Snake Game (Python, Pygame)

• Developed two games with collision detection, scoring logic, and increasing difficulty